<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../src-generated/schemas/fhir-single.xsd">
   <blockquote class="fhir-version-note">
  <p>
  This Implementation Guide is designed to use the R4 version of the HL7&#174; FHIR&#174; standard.<br /> 
  For information on submitting to our Direct FHIR endpoints using FHIR STU3, see the 
  <a href="CIBMTR_Direct_FHIR_API_Connection_Guide_STU3.pdf.pdf">Direct FHIR for STU3 Guide</a>.
  </p>
  </blockquote>
 <p>
  This FHIR Implementation Guide (IG) describes how to send data to CIBMTR via HL7&#174; FHIR&#174;.   
  </p>
  <a name="Introduction"> </a>
  <h3>Introduction</h3>
  <p>
  The <a href="https://www.cibmtr.org">Center for International Blood &amp; Marrow Transplant Research速 (CIBMTR速)</a>
  is a research collaboration between the <a href="https://bethematch.org/">National Marrow Donor Program速 (NMDP)/Be The Match速</a> 
  and the <a href="https://www.mcw.edu/">Medical College of Wisconsin (MCW)</a>. 
  The CIBMTR collaborates with the global scientific community to advance hematopoietic cell 
  transplantation (HCT) and other cellular therapy worldwide to increase survival and enrich 
  quality of life for patients. 
  </p>
  <p>
  The CIBMTR facilitates critical observational and interventional research through scientific 
  and statistical expertise, a large network of transplant centers, and a unique and extensive clinical outcomes database.
  CIBMTR collects data for HCT recipients using a web-based manual data entry system 
  (<a href="https://www.cibmtr.org/DataManagement/SystemApplications/FormsNet3">FormsNet</a>) 
  and an automated messaging system 
  (<a href="https://www.cibmtr.org/DataManagement/SystemApplications/AGNIS/Pages/default.aspx">A Growable Network Information System (AGNIS)</a>).
  </p>
  <p>
  CIBMTR is now collecting data through the <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir">HL7 Fast Healthcare Interoperability Resources&#174; (FHIR&#174;)</a> standard. 
  This IG describes the technical specification that CIBMTR accepts from third party clients producing FHIR resources for reporting HCT data.
  It is primarily based on the <a href="https://www.hl7.org/fhir/us/core/">US Core FHIR IG</a> which defines the minimum conformance 
  requirements for accessing patient data. 
  </p>
  <p>
  Initially, this IG is focused on information required for sending Patient demographic data that is necessary for creating or retrieving a CIBMTR 
  Research ID (CRID), and for reporting Patient resources with a known CRID. We have also begun specifying a profile for reporting laboratory observations, 
  focusing on a set of variables that have been identified as a priority for the CIBMTR Data Transformation Initiative in Fiscal Year 2021.
  </p>
  <a name="CRID"> </a>
  <h3>CRID Lookup/Creation</h3>
  <p>
  A REST API is available for enabling users to lookup and/or create CRIDs based on patient demographic
  information. This is described in <a href="CIBMTR_Direct_FHIR_API_Connection_Guide_STU3.pdf">Direct FHIR for STU3 Guide</a>. 
  This API does not use FHIR Patient resources, but instead uses a special JSON structure. 
  We are working on true FHIR interface for this function in the future where Patient FHIR resources may be submitted. 
  In the meantime, please use the method described <a href="CIBMTR_Direct_FHIR_API_Connection_Guide_STU3.pdf">here</a>.
  </p>
  <a name="Artifacts"> </a>
  <h3>Highlighted Artifacts</h3>
  <a name="Profiles"> </a>
  <h4>Profiles</h4>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-cibmtr-patient.html">CIBMTR Patient</a></li>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-cibmtr-observation-lab.html">CIBMTR Observation Laboratory Results</a></li>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-cibmtr-obs-priority-variables.html"></a>CIBMTR Observation for Priority Variables</li>
  </ul>
  <a name="ValueSets"></a>
  <h4>ValueSets</h4>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="ValueSet-cibmtr-priority-variables-2021.html">CIBMTR Priority Variables for FY21</a></li>
  </ul>
</div>